What about the missing child?
（圭一(けいいち)）
行方不明になった子供って…
The child's a year older than
you and named Satoshi Hojo.
（大石(おおいし)）年はあなたの１つ上で
名前は北条悟史(ほうじょうさとし)
（圭一）えっ？悟史？
Satoshi?
（圭一）なに？それ
What's that?
（伊知郎(いちろう)）さっき
レナちゃんが来てたじゃないか
Rena-chan was just here, right?
レナが…
Rena was...
（圭一）
そのとき確かにレナは来ていた
Rena was definitely
here at that time.
そして俺の部屋の前で…
She was right outside my room...
...and heard my
conversation with Oishi-san.
大石さんと俺の会話を…
Spirited Away by the Demon
Chapter Three, Suspicion
When They Cry
Behind where I looked back
(who's there in the front)?
I raised my nails in the dark
(and slashed the night).
Raindrops become droplets of
blood and drip down the throat.
If you don't have
a place to go back to...
...then stop here on my finger.
I'll take you away
along with that finger.
To the unopenable
forest where cicadas cry.
You can't turn back anymore.
What's wrong, Keiichi?
（藍子(あいこ)）どうしたの？圭一
（圭一）あっ…
You look pale.
（藍子）顔色悪いわよ
（圭一）ああ風邪かもしれない
I think it's a cold.
熱あるみたいだ
It seems like I have a fever.
（ドアチャイム）
（藍子）あらレナちゃん
Oh, Rena-chan.
I think she's here to get you.
（藍子）
迎えに来ちゃったんじゃない？
あっ休む　ごめん
I'm not going... Sorry.
（藍子）
じゃレナちゃんに伝えとくわ
Then I'll go tell Rena-chan.
Right.
（受付）前原(まえばら)さん診察室へどうぞ
Maebara-san,
come into the exam room.
（入江(いりえ)）風邪ですね
You have a cold.
Let's give you a shot.
注射でも打っておきましょう
Thank you.
（圭一）ありがとうございました
（受付）お大事に
Take care.
（受付）次の方どうぞ
Next person.
Oh, really?
（老人Ａ）あらホントに？
（老人Ｂ）やっぱり鬼隠しかいねえ
Is it really spiriting
away by the demon?
She's a young one.
She probably eloped.
（老人Ｃ）若い子だきゃあ
駆け落ちかもしられへん
どこの誰とよ？
With who?
東京者(もん)が来ちょったろう
カメラ持った
Remember the man from
Tokyo with the camera?
Probably with him.
あれ撮って…
Takano-san is strong.
鷹野(たかの)さんはしっかり者よ
（老人Ｂ）
どこ行ってもやっていけるけん
She'd do well no matter
where she lives.
“鷹野さん”？
Takano-san?
（圭一）ああ…あの人
Oh, her.
（受付）前原さん
（圭一）あっ…はい
Maebara-san.
Yes?
（大石）前原さんこんにちは
（圭一）ああ…
Maebara-san, hello!
（大石）
今日はどうしたんです？学校
What happened to school today?
ちょ…ちょっと体調悪かったんで
休みました
I-I wasn't feeling well,
so I didn't go.
I was about to have lunch.
私お昼に行こうとしてたんですよ
Would you like to come
with me to Okinomiya?
良かったら
ご一緒にいかがです？興宮(おきのみや)まで
O-Okay.
（大石）去年
悟史君が失踪したころから―
I've suspected something since
Satoshi went missing last year.
私は不審に感じていたんです
Thanks for waiting.
I've suspected something since
Satoshi went missing last year.
悟史君のお友達…
I investigated his friends...
...your group of friends
in other words, just a little bit.
つまり前原さんの
お友達グループの皆さんを―
Take your time.
...your group of friends
in other words, just a little bit.
ちょっぴりだけ
調べさせてもらったんです
（大石）１年目の事件の被害者は
現場の監督さんだったんですが
The first year's victim was the
director of the construction site...
事件の数週間前に園崎魅音(そのざきみおん)さんと
取っ組み合いをしてるんですよ
...but he had a few fights with
Mion Sonozaki a few weeks prior.
（大石）何度か…
（圭一）魅音と？
With Mion?
The dam-proponent couple had
an accident the second year, right?
（大石）２年目の事件で誘致派の
夫婦が事故に遭いましたよね
現場には
お嬢さんも一緒にいたんです
Their daughter was
also with them there.
それが北条沙都子(ほうじょうさとこ)さんなんです
That daughter
is Satoko Hojo-san.
えっ？サトコって…沙都子？
Satoko...
Satoko?
３年目には
神主夫婦が亡くなっていますよね
A priest and his wife
died the third year, right?
（大石）
そのお嬢さんが古手梨花(ふるでりか)さんです
Their daughter is Rika Furude.
梨花ちゃんが？
Rika-chan is...
The housewife that died the fourth
year is Satoko Hojo's aunt-in-law.
（大石）４年目に亡くなった主婦は
北条沙都子さんの義理の叔母です
当時沙都子さんは
ご両親を事故で失って―
At the time, she was taking care
of her due to her parents' deaths.
預けられていたんです
（圭一）ああ…
Also, the boy who went missing
the fourth year, Satoshi Hojo...
ちなみに
４年目 失踪した北条悟史さんは
沙都子さんの実の兄になります
...is Satoko's brother by birth.
This series
of mysterious deaths...
連続怪死事件の被害者は―
なぜかあなたのお友達グループに
全てつながるのです
...are all somehow connected
to your group of friends.
It must be a coincidence!
偶然に決まってるじゃないですか！
前原さん静かに
みんな見てますよ
Maebara-san, be quiet.
Everyone is looking.
あっ…す…すみません
S-Sorry.
Ryugu-san was living in the Ibaraki
prefecture suburbs till last year.
竜宮(りゅうぐう)さんは去年まで
茨城の郊外にお住まいでした
あっそうですよ！レナは違う
That's right. Rena's different.
Well, upon checking,
we found out that Ryugu-san...
実は調べてみたら
竜宮さんは引っ越す少し前に―
...was suspended from school
a few weeks before moving.
学校で
謹慎処分を受けているんですよ
I heard she went around school
and shattered all the windows.
（大石）なんでも学校中の
ガラスを割って回ったんだとか
（圭一）レナが？
Rena did?
A neurologist saw her and
prescribed drugs and therapy.
（大石）その後神経科に通院し
投薬とカウンセリングを
受けています
神経科って…
A neurologist...
（せきばらい）
その医師のカルテに―
There's a record of what she said
on the doctor's medical chart.
レナさんの会話内容が
記載されているんですがね
（大石）
その中に出てくるんですよ結構
A specific thing
appears numerous times.
What does?
何がです？
The word "Oyashiro-sama."
“オヤシロさま”って単語が…
（大石）“夜な夜な
それが枕元に立って―”
She said it stood by her pillow
nightly and looked down at her.
“自分を見下ろすんだ”って…
その後しばらくして
雛見沢(ひなみざわ)に引っ越されたんです
She moved to
Hinamizawa shortly after that.
Why would an outsider like her...
（圭一）なんでよそ者のレナが？
（大石）レナさんは
よそ者なんかじゃないですよ
Rena-san isn't an outsider.
I checked the residency records.
住民票で分かったんですが…
竜宮一家は元は雛見沢の住人です
The Ryugu family used
to live in Hinamizawa.
（大石）レナさんが
ちょうど小学校に上がるときに―
They moved to Ibaraki when
Rena entered grade school.
茨城へ引っ越されたんです
（圭一）じゃ…その…
Then what about
the last victim, Tomitake-san?
最後の被害者の富竹(とみたけ)さんは
どうなんですか？誰と接点が？
Who's he linked to?
全員ですよ
お忘れですか？前原さん
Everyone.
Did you forget, Maebara-san?
（大石）犠牲者は―
All the victims somehow have
connections to your friends.
なぜかあなたのお友達と
全員関係があるんです
Why are you telling me this?
（圭一）なんで俺に話すんですか？
Maebara-san...
前原さん危ないのは―
The one in danger...
...is you.
あなたなんですよ
（圭一）えっ？
How are you?
（魅音）具合はどう？
O-Okay.
I'm glad you seem okay.
（ﾚﾅ）元気そうで良かった
心配してたんだよ
（魅音）うんうん
We were worried.
悪かったな…
Sorry.
Looks like you're
not fully recovered yet.
（魅音）
まだ本調子じゃないみたいだね
（圭一）あっ…そ…そうか？
R-Really?
（ﾚﾅ）あっこれ
魅(み)ぃちゃんのおばあちゃんが―
Oh, here's some ohagi
that Mi-chan's grandma made.
作ってくれたおはぎだよ
（圭一）あっサンキュー
Thank you.
うん！あっその中にね
レナが作ったのも交じってるんだよ
Sure. Oh, one that
I made is also in there.
I wonder if you can
guess which it is.
圭一君に見つけられるかな？
This is your homework
after skipping today's club.
これ
部活を欠席した圭ちゃんへの宿題
We put letters on them,
so give us an answer tomorrow.
おはぎに
アルファベットがついてるから―
あした 回答すること
お前らお見舞いなのか
部活なのかどっちかにしろ！
Are you here to visit me
or for the club?
（圭一）ンンッ！
（魅音）うん元気元気！
You look fine.
You'll be fine tomorrow.
これならあしたは大丈夫そうだね
魅ぃちゃんもう行こう
あんまり騒いじゃ悪いよ
Let's go, Mi-chan.
It's rude to be too loud.
（魅音）そうだね
You're right.
Oh, by the way, Kei-chan...
（魅音）あっそうそう圭ちゃん
（圭一）何だよ？
What?
お昼なに食べた？
What did you eat for lunch?
えっ？お…表で食べたよ
I-I went out to eat.
ふ～ん…お昼は外食だったんだね
You went out for lunch.
How was it? Was it good?
（魅音）どう？おいしかった？
（圭一）アア…
渋いおじさまと
ご一緒だったみたいだけど誰？
It seemed like you
were with some old man.
Who was he?
Is he the same man
as last time? Is he?
ひょっとして
この間の人かな？かな？
H-How do you know?
（圭一）
な…なんでそんなことを？
So what were you talking about?
…で何のお話をしてたの？
随分と熱くなってたみたいだけど
It seemed you
were getting excited.
み…みんなの話はしてないよ
I-I didn't talk about you guys.
ふ～ん…なんだか怪しいな
Something's suspicious.
まあ何を隠れてやろうとも
あたしには全てお見通しってこと
Well, no matter what you hide,
I'll know what you're doing.
I just hope you won't forget that.
（魅音）それだけを
忘れないでくれればいいかな
Keiichi-kun, you look pale.
（ﾚﾅ）圭一君顔色悪いよ
Maybe you should lie down.
もう横になったほうがいいと思うな
（魅音）そうだね
I agree.
（魅音）あたしたちはもう帰ろう
We're going now.
（魅音）
あした学校休んじゃイヤだよ
Don't be absent tomorrow.
なんで…なんであいつら…
Why?
Why did they...
A-A-A needle?
は…針？アア…
When They Cry
（圭一）あいつらは
どうしてか知らないけど―
I don't know why,
but they're trying to kill me.
俺の命を狙ってる
ンンッ…くそ！
Damn it!
I won't let them
erase me that easily!
俺は
簡単には消されたりはしないぞ
No matter what.
絶対に！
私前原圭一は命を狙われています
I, Keiichi Maebara,
am in danger of getting killed.
I don't know why or who.
なぜ誰に命を狙われているのかは
分かりません
The only thing I know...
ただひとつ分かることは―
...is that it has something to do
with Oyashiro-sama's curse.
オヤシロさまのたたりと
関係があるということです
All right.
よし！
Oh, Keiichi-kun. You're alone
today, and you're early.
（老人）あら圭一君
今朝は１人で？早いねえ
目が覚めちゃったもんで
I woke up early.
Oh, really? Take care.
（老人）
そうかい　いってらっしゃい
（圭一）そうだ
ゆっくりなど寝ていられなかった
That's right...
I couldn't have slept.
Because I knew
exactly what I had to do.
俺のやるべきことは
はっきりとしていたから
ウワッ…アアッ！
Damn.
This is a...
これって…
ひき逃げ？
...hit and run?
Don't drop my guard.
I have to protect myself.
油断しちゃダメだ
自分の身は自分で守らないと
This is it.
これだ！
（子供たち）おはよう
Good morning!
（梨花）おはようございますです
（圭一）うん？
Good morning.
Oh my, you're early
today, Keiichi-san.
（沙都子）あらあらあら
今朝はお早いですわね圭一さん
（圭一）お…おう
Y-Yeah.
But why do you look like that?
（沙都子）しかし
何なんですの？その身なりは
N-No reason.
（圭一）ちょ…ちょっとな
（圭一）体がなまってさ
I felt out of shape, so I was
thinking of practicing swings.
…で
（沙都子）あっ！
素振りでも始めようかなってな
健康に気を遣うのは
とてもいいことだと思いますです
I think taking care of your
health is a really good thing.
Y-Yeah.
お…おう
But please don't lose that bat.
でもそのバット
なくさないでくださいねです
ウフッ…
エイッ！ ンンッ！
あれ？圭ちゃん
Hey, Kei-chan.
“先に行った”って言われて
驚いたけど
Hearing you went on
ahead surprised me.
あんた何やってるわけ？
What are you doing?
Can't you tell? I'm swinging!
（圭一）見て分かんないのかよ？
素振りだよ
For the national finals!
甲子園(こうしえん)だよ
National finals?
甲子園？
（圭一）ンンッ！
（魅音）ふ～ん…まあ頑張って
Well, good luck.
ンンッ…くそ！
Damn it!
くそ！くそ！
（圭一）くそ！
はいは～いみんな集合！
部活の時間だよ！
All right, gather up!
It's time for club!
What's for today? What?
今日は何かな？かな？
I won't lose.
負けませんわよ！
（梨花）み～！
Mi!
Hey, Kei-chan,
you're going home?
（魅音）
あれ圭ちゃん帰っちゃうの？
Maebara
Hey, Kei-chan,
you're going home?
I don't feel up for it.
（圭一）気分乗らないんだ
Can you leave
me alone for a bit?
しばらく放っといてくれないかな
（魅音）えっ？
圭一君やっぱり女の子と
一緒に遊ぶのなんか―
Keiichi-kun, so you don't like
to play with girls, do you?
イヤだったかな？かな？
（圭一）ンンッ…
Do you?
That's not what I mean.
（圭一）そういうわけじゃねえよ
What do you want?
何か用かよ？
べ…別にその…
N-Nothing, um, uh...
えっと…
（圭一）部活はどうしたんだよ？
What happened to club?
I was worried about you, so...
だって圭一君のこと心配で…
（圭一）もうついてくんなよ
Don't follow me anymore.
ついてくるなって言ってるだろう！
I said don't follow me!
あっだって
レナの家も同じ方向だし…
But my home is the same way.
（圭一）じゃ先行けよ！
レナが見えなくなったら行くから
Then go ahead of me.
I'll go when I can't see you.
I just want...
レナは圭一君と…
（圭一）早く行けよ！
Hurry up and go!
（圭一）早く！
あっ行くからそのバットやめてよ
I will, but put that bat down.
You're scaring me.
（ﾚﾅ）怖いよ…
（圭一）ンンッ…
立ち止まるな！
Don't stop!
U-Um, uh...
（ﾚﾅ）あ…あのその…
その…聞いてもいい？
Uh, can I ask you something?
What?
何だよ？
なんでバットまで同じなの？
Why do you have the same bat?
What are you talking about?
何言ってんだ？
だからなんで
バットまで同じなのかなって
Well, I was wondering why
you're carrying the same bat.
何言ってんだか全然分かんねえよ
もっとはっきり言え！
I don't get what you're saying!
Say it more clearly!
Why are you carrying
the same bat as Satoshi-kun?
（ﾚﾅ）だからどうして
バットまで悟史君と同じなの？
悟史って…
Satoshi?
Satoshi
（圭一）あっ！こ…これ…
T-This?
I borrowed it.
ちょっと借りたんだよ
いいだろうそれくらい
Who cares about that.
そんなことじゃないの！
（圭一）えっ？
That's not it!
Why are you doing
everything that Satoshi did?
悟史君のときとどうして…
どうしてそんなにまで同じなの？
何が同じって？
What's the same?
Although he joined a team,
he never played any sports.
（ﾚﾅ）チームに入っただけで―
スポーツなんか
しない人だったのに…
だ…だから…
（ﾚﾅ）悟史君もね…
S-So?
One day, Satoshi-kun suddenly
started walking to school alone too.
ある日突然
１人で登校するようになったの
Just like you.
圭一君みたいに…
And then suddenly one day,
he started practicing his swings.
（ﾚﾅ）そしてねある日突然
素振りの練習を始めたの
Just like you.
圭一君みたいに…
And then suddenly one day,
he started carrying a bat around!
そしてねある日突然
バットを持ち歩くようになったの
圭一君みたいに！
Just like you!
And then suddenly one day...
そしてねある日突然…
Suddenly...
（ﾚﾅ）突然…
Suddenly one day,
what happened to Satoshi?
（圭一）ある日突然
悟史はどうしたんだよ？
こ…答えろよレナ！
Answer me, Rena!
What happened to Satoshi?
言ったよね？圭一君
（圭一）アアッ…
I told you, Keiichi-kun.
Satoshi-kun transferred.
悟史君はね転校しちゃったの
ウッ！て…転校って…
T-Transferred?
You won't, right, Keiichi-kun?
しないよね？圭一君は
W-Won't what?
な…何をだよ？
転校
Transfer.
- Hello?
- Oh, Keiichi?
はい
（藍子）あっ圭一？
Oh, Mom.
ああ母さん
（藍子）お父さんとお母さんね―
Your father and I have
to go to Tokyo for work.
お仕事の関係で急に東京に
行かなくちゃならなくなったの
えっ？今から？
Right now?
ううんもう着いちゃってるの
お昼前には出発したからね
We're already here.
We left before noon.
な…何だよ？それ
W-What's that?
Your father's work
contract isn't going very well.
お父さんの仕事の契約がね
今ちょっとうまくいってないの
We'll be back tomorrow night.
You'll be okay by yourself, right?
帰るのは
あしたの晩になっちゃうけど
圭一 １人で大丈夫よね？
別に死にゃしないよ
It's not like I'll die.
Okay. Bye then.
そうじゃあね
あしたの朝ちゃんと起きるのよ
Make sure you wake up tomorrow.
And make sure you eat.
ご飯もちゃんと食べてね
（圭一）はいはい　そんじゃ
Yeah, yeah. Later.
Hello?
Good evening.
Sorry for calling so late.
（大石）どうも
夜分遅くに申し訳ありません
I'm Oishi from
the Okinomiya Bookstore.
私興宮書房の大石と…
（圭一）お…大石さんですか！
Oishi-san?
How is everything?
Did anything strange happen?
いかがですか？
その後何か変わったことは
ありませんか？
Uh, it seems like
someone's trying to kill me.
あっ その… やっぱり 俺…
命を狙われているみたいです…
（大石）本当ですか？
Really?
偶然の可能性もあるんですが…
It could be a coincidence, but...
レナと魅音がお見舞いってことで
置いていったおはぎの中に…
There was a needle in the ohagi
Rena and Mion gave me...
その…針が入ってたんです
...when they visited.
のみ込まずに済みましたが
これってやっぱり…
I didn't swallow it, but isn't this...
（大石）その針は？
And the needle?
あっえっと
よく見かけるような普通の裁縫針…
It was a common sewing needle.
No, Maebara-san,
the needle itself.
違いますよ前原さん針です
証拠になります
脅迫だと立証できるかもしれません
As evidence. We might be
able to use it as proof of a threat.
見つかりません
I can't find it.
あのときは
つい気が動転していて…
At the time,
I lost my train of thought.
そうですか…
I see.
Oh, that's not all.
あっあとそれだけじゃないんです
（圭一）実は今朝…
This morning...
Did you see
the van's license plate?
その車の
ナンバープレートは見ましたか？
あっ…す…すみません
S-Sorry.
（圭一）
白いワゴン車ってこと以外は…
I only know that
it was a white van.
Rena knows about how Satoshi
was spirited away by the demon.
（圭一）レナは知っています
鬼隠しに遭った悟史のことを
何か知っています
She knows something.
Can you clarify?
具体的には？
俺は悟史とそっくりらしいんです
It seems I'm exactly like Satoshi.
At this rate, she said I'll
face the same fate as Satoshi...
このままいくと
俺も悟史と同じ運命をたどると…
Be more specific.
（足音）
（大石）具体的には？
Like transfer.
（圭一）転校と…
Transfer?
（大石）転校？
実はレナの…
Actually, Rena...
To get my happiness,
I had done everything...
...but had done nothing
to be blamed and accused of.
The sound of footsteps
became louder every day.
Then I noticed the fact
there was no time.
I was a believer in life,
to be myself always.
And was asking
whether I would be alive.
Give me a reason
why not to adopt in this way.
Or judge me to be guilty
of so many incurable sins.
Tell me why or why not?
Complaining way too much.
Maybe I overlooked
something fatal for me.
Preview
（ﾅﾚｰﾀｰ）
怖がらないであしたの向こうを…
Preview
Don't fear what's
beyond tomorrow.
傷つけないであなたの心を…
Don't injure your heart.
Don't apologize for everything
that happened yesterday.
謝らないで昨日の全てを…
When They Cry.
「ひぐらしのなく頃に」
Spirited Away by the Demon
Chapter Four, Disturbance.
Chapter Four, Disturbance
Spirited Away by the Demon
Chapter Four, Disturbance.
あなたは信じられますか？
Can you believe it?